Contact

415-994-8148 (Mobile) cameron.geiser@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/cameron-geiser (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Engineering Management Management Professional Java

Certifications

AWS Certified Developer Associate

Patents

Method and system for matching purchase transaction history to real-time location information

Transaction and Payments Using Wearable Devices

Cameron Geiser

Client Application Dev Manager at Quicken

San Francisco, California, United States

Summary

I am an engineering manager with experience leading local and global full-lifecycle development teams. I most enjoy building up the processes, internal leadership and organization needed for teams to create and deliver quickly and with full autonomy.

I have hands-on experience leading teams of iOS, Android, QA, full stack web, Java and AWS engineers, and I work closely with upper management, design and product. My passion lies in navigating the friction where engineering, design and business goals meet.

Experience

Quicken

Engineering Manager November 2021 - Present (4 years) Menlo Park, California, United States

- Managed multiple React/Redux and React Native development teams, aligning with product and design stakeholders.
- Communicated project progress to upper management and PR teams, fostering transparency and collaboration.
- Oversaw the complete rewrite of our flagship web and mobile product, enhancing user experience, app performance and functionality.
- Led the development and production release of LifeHub, a Zero to One product.
- Build a team from 5 to 13 engineers. Mentored and hired several interns into full time roles.

East Avenue School
Remote School Headmaster
August 2020 - November 2021 (1 year 4 months)
Montara, California, United States

PIX System
Director of Client Application Development
Page 1 of 4

October 2018 - August 2020 (1 year 11 months)

San Francisco, California, United States

- Directed local and international engineering teams to develop iOS, web, tvOS, and native desktop applications.
- Led the hiring and onboarding process for new team members.
- Established and implemented best practices and scrum methodologies.

Capital One

8 years 3 months

Senior Manager, Streaming Data January 2018 - September 2018 (9 months)

San Francisco, California, United States

Led a team of engineers in the design and development of the company's custom enterprise data management solutions, focusing on data lineage. These applications power the understanding of the company's petabytes of data.

Tech stack: Java, Kubernetes, AWS EC2 and RDS, Docker and AWS Neptune.

Helped lead Capital One's sponsorship of the University of California Berkeley's RISE Lab focusing on real-time machine learning on large data sets.

Senior Manager & Technical Lead, Small Business Mobile January 2014 - January 2018 (4 years 1 month)

San Francisco, CA

Recruited, hired and managed a cross-functional team of 35 local and remote technical professionals, including managers. Duties included communicating closely with upper management, cross-functional engineering teams, product teams, design teams. Developed team members into leadership roles. Released multiple customer facing Mobile Apps for iOS and Android, Java REST APIs and fully-automated CI/CD testing pipeline using Jenkins, AWS, Github, Fastlane, Ruby, and other technologies.

Senior Manager, Capital One Labs April 2012 - February 2014 (1 year 11 months) San Francisco CA

Founding member of Capital One Labs and technology evangelist. Our mission was to transform Capital One into a leader in digital banking.

Lead Software Engineer, BankOns Inc. (acquired by Capital One)

July 2010 - April 2012 (1 year 10 months)

San Francisco, CA

- Co-Founder and technical lead
- Developed web and mobiles using LAMP, iOS, Android, Java, MySQL, and AWS
- Winner of Finovate 2011 "Best of Show":

https://finovate.com/videos/finovatespring-2011-bankons/

Acquired by Capital One in April 2012

Med-Vantage

Software Engineer

October 2008 - April 2010 (1 year 7 months)

Java Swing desktop application development & UI Design Lead. Worked closely with design and product partners to deliver on tight roadmap timelines.

- Java, Java Swing, SQL, Oracle, MySQL
- T-SQL Procedures

Quinstreet Inc

Java Developer

November 2004 - June 2008 (3 years 8 months)

Java Swing desktop application development & web development.

- Java, Java Swing, SQL, Oracle, JDBC, Hibernate
- · JavaScript, CSS and HTML web development

Louis Vuitton

Web Developer

September 2002 - November 2004 (2 years 3 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Web and database development for eCommerce application.

- · JavaScript web development
- Servlet and JSP development
- · Oracle, SQL & PL/SQL
- Adobe Photoshop

Estee Lauder

Web Developer

June 2000 - June 2002 (2 years 1 month)

San Francisco Bay Area

Web development for eCommerce application.

· Java, JavaScript, HTML, SQL, Oracle

• ATG Dynamo, Servlets, web development, XML/XSL

Education

U. C. Berkeley

BA, Political Science & Computer Science · (August 1986 - May 1991)

University of Virginia Darden School of Business Capital One Technology Leadership Program, Executive Education · (2018 - 2018)

SF State University

Computer Science · (January 1993 - June 1996)